blr.com 2019-12-31

# 

BLR, Inc. respects the privacy of our users. We have created this policy in order to demonstrate our privacy commitment to our users. By coming to a BLR site, you are agreeing to and accepting this Privacy Policy as well as the terms and conditions or other end user agreement for that site. In many instances, you may opt-out of uses of your Indentifying Information (defined below) allowed under this Policy, as described at the end of this Policy.

  * We will not distribute information that identifies you individually or reveals your identity ("Identifying Information") unless you give your prior approval in response to a request made by BLR or unless distribution of this information is permitted under this Privacy Policy. Your electronic approval will qualify as your consent for this purpose. Postings by you that contain Identifying Information should be done with care as discussion forums and the like are public and may be viewed by all users. You should use caution when deciding to disclosure your personal information.
  * We may share Indentifying Information with regulatory or other legal authorities if requested to do so by a court or other government or law enforcement authority.
  * We may collect and use information about you and your use of the BLR sites, including Identifying Information, for our own internal purposes such as, for example, analyzing usage of the BLR sites in order to improve them.
  * We may use, aggregate and/or distribute information about you and your use of the BLR sites in ways that do not identify you individually or reveal your identity.
  * Advertisements, promotional offers, promotional e-mails, "free gifts," and links, for example, on the BLR sites or sent via e-mail or other means from BLR may ask for Identifying Information from you. If you provide this information, your Identifying Information may be provided (either directly from you or by BLR) to the advertiser or Web site or company making the offer or providing the gift. 
  * If you are using a co-branded site of BLR and at least one other third party (indicated by the inclusion of another party's name or product/service name either in the URL or site or by the inclusion of a third party's(ies') logos or trademarks in the site), your Identifying Information may be used and/or distributed by BLR pursuant to this Privacy Policy and by the other party(ies) pursuant to this Policy and/or their applicable policy(ies).
  * BLR may send users, via e-mail or other means, information relating to BLR sites and/or information on specials, new products and/or promotions from our marketing partners/colleagues. The information described in these messages is intended to be of high interest or value to our users. To choose not to receive such messages, a user can simply click or go to a URL link located in the e-mail or other message, which will remove the user from future mailings. Or, for certain sites a user may edit his/her personal account information, which contains an option on receiving special offers, at any time by clicking the appropriate link on the applicable BLR site.
  * Occasionally we make our customer list available to other reputable organizations so you may receive offers you might find interesting. Sporadically we permit carefully selected organizations to advertise in our e-mail publications, let them sponsor product alerts or will sponsor their product offers. To stop receiving such e-mails, follow the unsubscribe instructions in the e-mail or send an e-mail to [Service@BLR.com](mailto:Service@BLR.com) at any time.
  * In the course of our business, BLR might buy or sell sites or assets. In these kinds of transactions, customer information (such as Identifying Information) is usually one of the transferred business assets. In the event that BLR, its parent, subsidiaries, or affiliates is acquired, merged, or otherwise combined with another party, customer information (such as Identifying Information) will be one of the transferred assets.
  * BLR may use other companies and persons to perform certain functions for us. These functions might include, for example, processing credit card payments, providing customer service, and sending e-mail. These other companies and persons may have access to customer information (such as Identifying Information) that's needed to perform their functions, but they are not authorized to use it for any other purposes. 
  * We may share Identifying Information with affiliated companies, business partners and joint venturers, for example, but, we use reasonable efforts to require those companies to honor the confidentiality of such Indentifying Information.

In order to provide our users with a more complete understanding of how the BLR sites collect and use information from our users, we have provided the following information: 

**Internet Protocol (IP) Address**

The BLR sites log IP addresses for systems administration, diagnostic, and site tracking purposes, and to report aggregate information to advertisers. The BLR sites do not link IP addresses to information identifying users individually. 

**Cookies**

The BLR sites use files called "cookies" to store usernames, passwords, and other user preferences so that users don't have to re-enter this information each time they use a particular BLR site. You should be aware that advertisers serving ads on the BLR sites may use their own cookies. 

We, or a data provider we have engaged, may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser to enable you to receive customized ads, content or services. No personally identifiable information is placed into these cookies. The cookies may reflect de-identified demographic or other data linked to data you voluntarily have submitted to us, e.g., your email address, in hashed, non-human readable form. To opt-out of these cookies or learn more please go to <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>.

**Information Collection**

The BLR sites' registration forms ask users to enter contact information (like their e-mail address), general information (like their city, state), and demographic information (like their zip code, age, or income level). The forms also require unique identifiers (username and password) so that users can be verified when they access the BLR sites. The contact information primarily is used to send users e-mails and other information they have requested and other information as stated in this Privacy Policy. The demographic information may be used among other things, to tailor users' experiences at the BLR sites, distribute and show you content that we think you might be interested in, and display site content according to your preferences.

Additionally, emails we send may contain a bit of code known as a "web beacon." This code allows us to understand the time and date of when a user has opened an email and when he/she has utilized a link within the email to visit a website. Our web beacons do not collect personally identifiable information. Users wishing to disable our web beacons should do so by turning images "off" in their email client (e.g., Outlook, Outlook Express). Please see your email client for more information."

Advertisers or Web sites that have links on the BLR sites may collect personally identifiable information about you. The privacy and information practices of those advertisers or Web sites linked to the BLR sites are not covered by this Privacy Policy. 

Some BLR websites use VWO web analytics service. These services may record mouse clicks, mouse movements, scrolling activity, as well as text you type in the website. VWO is not using the information to collect any personally identifiable information entered into the website. VWO does not track your browsing habits across websites that are not using these services. Information collected VWO are used on an aggregate basis to improve site usability. You can opt out from these services by visiting their site: <https://vwo.com/opt-out/>

BLR websites also use a service called Lytics, which helps us learn how visitors engage with our site and helps us to improve site experience. Cookies are used to collect information in an anonymous form, and include where visitors have come to the site from and the pages they visited while on our site. The information that is collected is non-personal information including standard internet log information; referring domain; pages visited; geographic location (country only); preferred language used to display the webpage; date and time when website pages were accessed; and details on your behavior within our BLR sites. Lytics cookies are stored on your browser and expire automatically after 365 days.

**Changes to this Privacy Policy**

This Privacy Policy is subject to modification from time to time. You may be notified: (1) in an e-mail sent to the e-mail address you have provided to BLR through the BLR sites, or (2) BLR's posting of a notice for at least 30 days on this Web site or the applicable BLR site that the BLR sites Privacy Policy has been changed. Your continued use of the BLR site after such change shall be deemed your acceptance of such change.  If you do not accept such change, you should stop using the BLR site.

**Opt-Out; Correcting Information**

You may opt out of having Identifying Information used for non-essential purposes, disclosed to third parties or used to send promotional correspondence by contracting BLR at the mailing address or email address below.  You may also correct information in your registration form by contacting us at the address below. To ensure that your intention in the email is clear, you should include the words “opt-out” and “Indentifying Information” in the subject field of such email. If you have any questions regarding this policy, please contact: 

Customer Service  
BLR, Inc.  
141 Mill Rock Road East  
Old Saybrook, CT 06475
